So in the previous video we talked about how to test your formulas,
在之前的视频中，我们谈到了 如何测试你的公式，
how to make sure that the results they deliver are within reasonable boundaries,
如何确保他们 提供的结果是在合理范围之内，
for example,
例如，
but there's another way we can test. What's also very important in
但还有另一种方式，我们是可以用于测试。 在
spreadsheet testing
电子表格测试里，另一个极其重要的项目是
is validating user input. If you look at this spreadsheet,
验证用户的输入。 如果你看一下 这个电子表格 ，
this Selling Price right here, it's an input value.
“售价”就在这里，它是一个 输入值。
A user puts in that input and he could make a mistake.
一名用户在输入框中输入，他 犯了一个错误。
And we want to let the user know as early as possible
我们希望让用户 尽早知道
that he has made a mistake. For instance, if we enter new item here,
他已经犯了一个错误。 例如， 如果我们在这里输入新的项目，
the Stone Table,
“石桌”，
if I make a mistake and I accidentally input a negative number,
如果我犯了一个错误，不小心 输入了一个负数，
then, suppose we would have a check on the percentages,
那么，若我们检查 百分比的值数，
we would know, because we see now that percentage is off the chart, so
我们应该可以发现这项错误，因为我们所看到的 百分比将不会与我们预期的一样，所以
that cannot be correct. But there are more subtle ways in which we could make
不可能是正确的。 但我们也可能以更难察觉的方式
a mistake. Maybe we entered the same number twice,
犯下一个错误。 也许我们输入了一个数字 两次，
and then this percentage is zero, which might be okay, that might still be
然后这个百分比为零，这 可能是正确的，仍然可能
within the boundaries. So what we want to have is
在边界之内。 因此，我们想要的是
for fields, for cells, where spreadsheet users
对于字段，对于单元格，其中电子表格 用户
add their input, have some validation rule
添加输入，在上头有一些验证 规则
right on top of that. Here is another example of validating user input.
。 这里是另一个验证用户输入的例子。
If we look at this register import, we see
如果我们看一下进口注册， 我们看到
all the codes of the items that we have been selling,
我们售卖物品的所有代码，
and this formula, the Category formula,
以及这个公式，“类别”公式，
it just chops off the first item, the first character of
它只是砍掉第一项，文本 的第一个字符
the text and put it in a list. So suppose
，并将其放入列表。 所以 假设
we add a Pivot Table on top of that data, calculating
我们在该数据的基础上添加数据透视表， 计算
the profit per category, we need to be sure that that category is actually
每个类别的利润，我们需要 确保这一类别实际上是
an existing category,
现有类别，
that is actually in our list of categories, and we have another worksheet
这实际上是在我们的 类别列表中，我们有另一个工作表
where we keep track of the categories. We would want the user to know
记录类别。 我们 希望用户知道
if faulty input is provided, a code is given with no associated category,
如果用户提供错误的输入，将给出一个没有相关类别的代码，
we would like the user to have an error. And a lot more validation
我们要用户得到一个 错误信息。 而且在输入工作表里还有更多的验证
is possible in this input worksheet - I'm not going to tell you how, because this
方式 - 我 不会告诉你这些方式是什么，因为这
is one of this week's
是这个星期的
exercises. So you can start thinking about it right now!
练习之一。 所以，你已经可以开始思考 了！
How would you validate the user input in this spreadsheet?
你将如何在此电子表格 里验证用户的输入？
tests is, you remember from the previous video, that spreadsheets only one in three
一点是，你记得以前的 视频中，3个电子表格里仅有
have a manual.
一个有使用手册。
And you might think: what this documentation
你可能会想：那些 文件
have to do with testing? Those are two entirely different topics.
和测试有什么关系？ 这 完全是两个不同的主题。
That's really not true! Tests
但这真的不是这样的！ 测试
can serve as means of documentation.
可以达到作为文档的用途。
If you put a test in your spreadsheet
如果你把一个测试运用在你的电子表格里，
the test tells a user of the spreadsheet something
此测试方式将告诉用户关于那电子表格
about it. If I look at this formula here, so I have added a formula that checks
的一些事情。 如果我在这里看这个公式， 因此我添加了一个公式检查
whether a given item has an existing category and if it doesn't,
一个给定的项目是否具有现存目录 ，如果没有，
here you have a code that starts with an X,
在这里，你有X开头的代码，
if there is no associated category, you get an error.
如果不存在相关联的目录，则 得到一个错误。
So this test tells a story, this test expresses
因此本次测试讲述了一个故事，本次测试 告诉
to the user that only existing categories
用户只有 现有类别
can be input. Otherwise, something is wrong.
可以被输入。 否则，就会 出错。
So in this way you can use tests to communicate
所以用这种方式，你可以使用测试 沟通
information about your input to your future self,
你输入的信息 和未来的自己，
if you still work with the spreadsheet in five years, or maybe one
如果你五年后仍使用 电子表格，或者
of the 11 other people that are using a spreadsheet.
其他11人中1人仍使用 电子表格 。
So tests are means of documentation,
因此，测试也起到文档的作用，
in addition to, of course, their purpose as
除了本来的用途 如
actually checking for errors.
检查错误。